我知道这听起来很扯
I'm well aware it sounds bananas.
但如果你了解化石记录
But looking at the fossil record,
具备我对感染的知识
knowing what I know about this infection,
你也会觉得
you cannot say for certain
这可能是恐龙灭绝的原因
it isn't what killed off the dinosaurs.
我相信这种理论吗
Now, do I believe that's what happened?
不信
No.
但是想想甲龙行尸追着梁龙
But it's enjoyable as hell to think about an undead ankylosaur
感觉爽爆了
going after a diplodocus.
这个电子游戏值得预定
That there is a video game worth a preorder.
太棒了  有发现
Oh, hell, yeah. Score.
再捡几个
A few more of those,
来点铝箔和漂白剂
a little aluminum foil and some bleach,
就能产生电压了  妹子
you got yourself some volts, sister.
自制电池
Homemade battery.
-给  -真的吗
- Here. - For reals?
你不想要吗
You don't want it?
真的
For reals.
非常感谢
Much obliged.
说到电子游戏  你喜欢玩哪种
Speaking of video games, what kind of gamer were you?
角色扮演  飞行射击  模拟赛车
RPGs, shmup, sim racing?
你睡吧  我来守
Go to sleep. I got this.
无意冒犯  但我不放心让你保护尤金
No offense, but I'm not leaving Eugene's life in your hands.
你跟我们一起是因为你需要帮助
You came with us because you wanted help.
我需要你的帮助  不需要你站岗
You are support, not point.
我们会和你一起往北走
We'll move north with you
直到我在路边找到合适的车辆
till I find the right vehicle just off the tracks.
然后五个人就会变成三个
Then five becomes three.
或者两个
Or two.
我们都有自己的任务
We each have our missions.
你得睡会儿
You need to get some sleep.
我还没见你睡过呢
I haven't seen you do it yet.
我之前以为你爱上了他
Thought it was because you were in love with him.
爱上一个男人的女孩
A girl in love with a guy,
努力帮他找到女友
she's trying to help get to his girl.
如果真是那样
If that were the case...
闭上双眼就太难受了
closing your eyes would be just too damn tragic.
-真是那样就好了  -对
- If that were the case. - Yeah.
我看见了罗西塔给你端晚餐时
I saw the way you were looking down Rosita's shirt
你看着她的衬衫里面的样子
while she was serving you dinner.
那玩意儿有一种催眠的魔力
Hey, the things are damn near hypnotic.
尤金整天盯着她的屁股看
Look, Eugene spends half the day staring at her ass.
我不怪你  这只能说明我之前猜错了
I'm not mad, it just means my theory's shot.
我真心抱歉
I'm awfully sorry about that.
我有对有错
Well, I'm right and I'm wrong.
是因为你做过的事  还是你没做到的事
Something you did or something you didn't do?
我做过的事
Something I did.
你也当过兵
You were in the army.
我懂那一套"团队合作
I get the whole gung ho,
任务就是你的生命"的屁话
mission is your life bullshit.
-是啊  你懂  -是啊
- Yeah, you do. - Yeah.
所以我们都有理由
So we both got our reasons.
都有任务
Both got our missions.
你的任务结束后  你要做什么
What do you do when the mission's over?
我只是被惹恼了
Been rubbing me wrong, is all.
我是个讲公平的绅士
I'm an even-Steven type gentleman.
你帮我找到补给品
You help me find the supplies,
我们会分享电池和发出的电力
we'll share the battery and whatever juice we scare up,
虽然微不足道
minimal as it may be.
成交吗
Deal?
格伦  去终点站
玛姬  萨沙  鲍勃
欢迎所有人
抵达就能活命
格伦  去终点站
玛姬  萨沙  鲍勃
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  33来了
翻译  蘑菇
翻译  送小h
翻译  重案组李Sir
翻译  卫老哥
翻译  Marshal
听译  CS漫画家小明
校对  卫老哥
翻译/校对  送小爷  送小孩
时间轴  送小爷  送小森
时间轴  雪贵人
后期  、青衣
特效/后期  送二哥
总监  送小孩
行尸走肉
第四季  第十五集
我来吧
I got it.
看来那只三脚猫还是辜负了我们啊
Looks like that Robin Hood cat cut out on us after all.
我还以为他没胆子一个人走掉
I didn't think he had the sack to go out on his own.
他没走  他的东西还在
He don't. Dude left his stuff here.
也许只是早上去拉屎了
Probably just stepped out to drop a morning deuce.
我们还剩一天的水
I think we got about a day's worth of water left.
幸亏天气凉快了些  但是
We're lucky it's cooled off a little bit, but...
你们在干什么
What are you doing?
-赢得赌注  -你做梦
- Winning a bet. - In your dreams.
我还在铁轨上哦
I'm still on.
你高兴得太早了  聪明蛋
You spoke too soon, wise guy.
我们可能要走很久
This might go on a while.
要不你们快点
Maybe we can speed this up.
是啊  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
不应该瞎闹
Shouldn't be fooling around.
我们应该  卡尔
We should probably-- Carl!
我赢了
I win.
交出来
Pay up.
那真是最后一根巧克力棒了吗
Is that really the last Big Cat?
别这样
Oh, come on.
你说赢了的人可以随便选
Hey, but you said winner's choice.
好吧  拿着吧  是你的了
Go ahead, take it. It's yours.
你赢得正大光明
You won it fair and square.
拿着吧  我们总是分着吃
Come on, we always share.
递过来吧
Fork it over.
你这是干嘛
What the hell are you doing?
弄点早餐吃
Catching me some breakfast.
是我的
That's mine.
是我的箭先射到的
My arrow's the one that hit first.
这只兔子应该归我
The cottontail belongs to me.
日出之前我就守在这了
Been out here since before the sun came up.
打猎的规矩
You see, the rules of the hunt
在这儿不算数
don't mean jack out here.
你手里拿的兔子
Now, that rabbit you're holding
我要了  小子
is claimed, boy.
不管你乐不乐意  我都要了
Claimed whether you like it or not.
我要是你  我就交出来
So I was you, I'd hand it over.
赶紧交出来
Now before you get to wishing
不然你会后悔今早起了床
you ain't never even got out of bed this morning.
这不是你的
It ain't yours.
我敢打赌
You know, I'll bet
有个小贱人
this bitch
把你的脑子弄得一团糟
got you all messed up, hmm?
我说得对吗
Am I right?
让你像一个魂不守舍的
Got you walking around here like a dead man
活死人一样四处晃荡
who just lost himself a piece of tail.
那小妞肯定很不错
Must have been a good'un.
跟我说说
Tell me something.
那小妞是不是个幼齿
Was it one of the little'uns?
幼齿在这里可活不久
'Cause they don't last too long out here.
冷静  伙计们  冷静点
Easy, fellas, easy.
把武器先放下
Let's just put our weapons down.
看看能不能把问题解决了
See if we can't figure out what's really the problem here, huh?
-你喊"我要了"吗  -当然了
- Did you claim it? - Hell, yeah.
那就结了  兔子属于伦
Well, there you go. That critter belongs to Len.
赶紧给我吧
So let's have it.
看起来你想知道是怎么回事
Looks like you may be wanting an explanation.
独自行动  如今已经行不通了
See, going it alone, that ain't an option nowadays.
但是  仍然是优胜劣汰
Still, it is survival of the fittest.
这有点矛盾了
That's a paradox right there.
所以我制定了一些规矩
So I laid out some rules of the road
来防止丛林法则分分钟上演
to keep things from going Darwin every couple hours.
让大家无压力地和平相处
Keep our merry band together and stress-free.
你要做的就是喊一句"我要了"
All you got to do is claim.
你可以这样标记你的领土
That's how you mark your territory,
你的猎物  还有睡觉的床
your prey, your bed at night.
就喊一句"我要了"
One word, claimed.
我才不喊
I ain't claiming nothing.
我们应该教训他  是吧
We're gonna teach him, right?
按规矩我们得教训他
The rules say we got to teach him.
因为你违反了一条你不知道的规矩
It wouldn't be fair to punish you
就惩罚你有些不公平
for violating a rule you never even knew existed.
才没有什么规矩
There ain't no rules no more.
有的  你知道的
Oh, there are. You know that.
所以我才没有把你杀掉  抢走你的弩
That's why I didn't kill you for the crossbow.
冷静  伙计
Easy there, partner.
"我要了"
Claimed.
一句就够了
That's all you got to say.
有屁股吃也比没有强
Hey, ass end is still an end.
等等
Hold up!
我们在这里休息
We're stopping here.
累了反应就慢了
Tired is slow.
-反应慢就会死  -还不到中午
- Slow is dead. - It's barely noon.
我才他妈的不管
I don't give a monkey's left nut.
自从我们玩命般赶路之后
None of us has slept more than a couple hours straight
已经很久没好好睡上一觉了
since we went all Casey Jones.
这地方看起来很安全
This place looks safe.
我们需要休息一下
We need to rest.
我明白  你想找到她
I get it. You have to find her.
但罗西塔和我也有任务
Well, Rosita and me, we got a mission, too.
就是让这个男人活下去
It's keeping that man alive,
把他带到华府
getting him to Washington,
然后拯救他妈的全世界
and saving the whole damn world.
所以我们要进这个塔楼  现在就进
So we're going in that tower and we're going now.
该死
Oh, crap.
小心  快走  快走
Watch out! Go, go!
-快走  -走开  走开
- Go! - Move! Move!
-你还好吧  -我没事
- Are you okay? - I'm fine.
我们得留在这儿  谁来帮忙抬一下她
We got to stay here. Who's gonna help me carry her up?
-你没事吧  -没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你是想停下还是继续走
You wanna stop or you wanna keep going?
不用  继续走  我没事
No, keep going. I'm good.
-你确定  -对  是的
- You sure? - Yeah. Yeah.
看  假如她都能走
Look, if she can keep going,
那我们也能走
we can all keep going.
或者你们可以留在这里
Or you guys can stay here.
你们不需要我们  我们也不需要你们
You don't need us, we don't need you.
-没关系的  -你真是个混蛋
- It's okay. - Wow, you're an ass.
你说什么她都照做是因为她觉得亏欠你
She will do whatever you say because she thinks she owes you.
拿出点男人的样子
Man up.
在这儿停几个小时
Stay here for a few hours.
你只在乎尤金的安全  是吧
You just care about keeping Eugene safe, right?
所以你才想停下
It's the only reason you want to stop?
我们一直走到太阳落山
We go until sundown,
我把防暴服给尤金
I give Eugene my riot gear
现在就给
right here, right now.
-皆大欢喜  -除了她
- Everybody wins. - Except her.
你不是她妈妈
You're not her mama.
她说她能走  她就能走
She says she can walk, she can walk.
就按你说的办吧
You got yourself a deal.
好
Okay.
你有什么计划  达里尔
So what's the plan, Daryl?
为什么这么问
How so?
你虽然跟我们搭伴  但你很快会走是吧
You're with us now, but you ain't soon?
是的
Yep.
所以问你有什么计划
So what's the plan?
就想找个合适的地方
Just looking for the right place is all.
我们对你而言不够好是吧
Oh, we ain't good enough for you, huh?
你们中的一些人可算不上友善
Some of you ain't exactly friendly.
你自己就不太友善
You ain't so friendly yourself.
你知道在这外面你需要一个团队的
You know you need a group out here.
-说不定我不需要  -不  你需要
- Maybe I don't. - No, you do.
你应该和我们待在一起
You should be with us.
大家不一定要友善待人
People don't got to be friendly.
我们不一定要做好人
We don't have to be nice.
也不一定要成为手足兄弟连
We don't have to be brothers in arms.
我们只需要守规矩
We just got to follow the rules.
想要什么你得说一声
You claim.
假如你偷东西  你就得死
If you steal, you keel.
我知道这听起来有点搞笑
I know that sounds a little funny,
但是丢东西时就没人笑得出来了
but nobody laughs when something goes missing.
而且你不能撒谎
And you don't lie.
因为一旦开始就停不下来了
'Cause that's a slippery slope indeed.
假如你坏了规矩怎么办
What happens if you break 'em?
你会挨揍
Oh, you catch a beatin'.
揍的轻重取决于你的行为有多过分
The severity of which depends upon the offense
以及那天大家的态度
and the general attitude of the day.
但是这种事不常发生
But that don't happen much
因为一旦我们这种人守规矩了
'cause when men like us follow rules
并且相互合作一下
and cooperate a little bit,
世界就是我们的了
well, the world becomes ours.
就那儿了
Right there.
我们今晚的住处
It's our abode for the evening.
不是"我们"
There ain't no us.
你现在就要走吗
You leaving right now?
不走吗
No?
那看来就是"我们"了
Then it sure seems like there's an us.
你爱猫吗  达里尔
You a cat person, Daryl?
我爱
I am.
从三岁时就爱猫
Loved 'em since I was three years old.
恶劣的生物
Vicious creatures.
总之  我告诉你
Anyway, I'll tell you,
这是真的
and this is true,
把自己当成家猫的野猫
ain't nothing sadder than an outdoor cat
是最可悲的
that thinks he's an indoor cat.
我们离他们越来越近了
We're gaining on 'em.
依然是湿的
Still wet.
和打了光亮剂一样  没法从这上去
We sure as Shinola can't go up and over.
绕过去怎么样
How about around?
不妥
No.
绕过去至少要花一天
That'll take a day, maybe more.
既然玛姬走了这里  我也要走
If Maggie went through, I'm going through.
-我们很接近了  -先别说话
- We're close. - Shut up a second.
你们听到了吗
You hear that?
那可是一条漫长幽暗的隧道
That there is a long, dark tunnel
里面有无数蠢蠢欲动的行尸
full of reanimated corpses.
要带尤金从这穿过去
I don't have full-on certainty
我没有十足的把握能把他活着带出去
that I can get Eugene through there alive.
我的建议是  多花一天时间
My recommendation would be take the day,
绕过这里  小心驶得万年船
make the detour and play it safe,
我猜你肯定不会接受
but I know you're not gonna do that.
所以  我们要在这里分别了
So this is where we've got to part ways.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你得靠自己了
You're on your own.
不  你不是一个人
No, you're not.
不  这些是你们的
No, no, no. Those are yours.
你们长途跋涉  需要这些东西
You guys will need them for your trip.
你也一样
You will, too.
多谢
Thank you.
对不起
Sorry, I...
我打了你一拳
hit you in the face.
打得好
I'm not.
我喜欢打架
I like to fight.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
别那么混蛋了
Try not to be an ass.
你们都是好人
You're both good people.
我不得不承认  你真的很正点  塔拉
I have to say that you are seriously hot, Tara.
多谢  不过我喜欢女人
Yeah, I like girls.
我看出来了
I'm well aware of that.
如果你们在里面遇到麻烦
Say you get into trouble in there.
转身往回走
You turn around.
我们循原路折回到第一条路
We're doubling back to the first road we crossed.
或许在我们找到车之前  你们能赶上我们
Maybe you find us before we find the right ride.
谢谢
Thanks.
我知道你现在的心情
I know what you're going through.
在这一切开始之后
After this all started,
在我意识到自己再也见不到亲人
after I realized I'd never see my family,
和朋友之后
my friends again,
我麻木了
I was numb.
日复一日  茫然无措
All day long, just numb.
我只想说  我懂你的感受
I'm just saying I get it.
当布莱恩宣称他想要接管监狱时
When Brian told us he wanted to take over the prison,
我就知道不太对劲
I knew it sounded bad.
我找到我女友的时候  她已经死了
When I found my girlfriend, she was dead.
我的外甥女
My niece.
我姐姐
My sister,
她被团团围住  遭到了疯狂的袭击
she was surrounded, pounced on.
我目睹了一切
I saw it happen.
但这些与他对玛姬父亲做的事
But still, it wasn't as bad as seeing
比起来微不足道
what he did to Maggie's father.
当时我就醒悟了
Because that's when I knew.
刀落下的那一刻
That second the sword--
我想大喊不要  但于事无补
I wanted to scream "No," But it just happened.
布莱恩说我们可能要杀人
Brian said we might have to kill people.
我是第一个主动加入的
I was the first to jump in.
我以为只是"可能"而已
I was just hanging on the "Might."
这里没有行尸
They ain't here.
很久没来过人了
Nobody's been here for a while.
最后来的人把汽油都带走了
Whoever was, they got all the gas.
没关系
That don't matter.
我们越来越近了  我能感觉到
We're getting closer. I can feel it.
我要了
Claimed.
血还是湿的
The blood is still wet.
一定是今天才发生的
This had to have happened today.
拿着
Hold this.
格伦  你干什么
Glenn. What are you doing?
-她不在里面  -什么
- She's not one of them. - What?
地上没有血
There's no bodies on the ground.
这说明玛姬过去了
That means Maggie made it through.
她过去了
She made it through.
我们必须干掉它们
We have to get rid of them.
-没有足够的弹药了  -那就冲过去
- We don't have enough ammo. - Then we'll push through.
我们必须走其他的路
We have to find another way.
你保护他
You got him?
我搞定它
I got her.
得把这车发动起来
Gonna need to air this baby out.
很好  这样我们就有时间找回原路了
Good, it'll give us some time to figure out how to get back on track.
别伤害我妈妈
-别别  -我是导航员
- Yo, no, no. - I'm the navigator.
那就学着导航啊
Then learn to navigate.
记得汤普森吗
Remember Thompson?
我正式要求你对我当面道歉
I'm formally requesting a straight up do-over on that one.
我带领大家
I guided us here from Houston
从休斯顿平安抵达乔治亚北部
to northern Georgia without incident.
我看并非完全"平安"吧
I wouldn't say without incident.
只出了小意外
Minimal incident.
至少路线没错
Navigation-wise, at least.
拜托了
Please?
如果由你来导航
I cannot abide a reality
那让我这个带领大家历经险阻
where you are the chosen navigator over a son of the South
成功走过现实与虚幻之旅的
who has successfully negotiated the travails
南方之子颜面何在
and vagaries of journeys both real and virtual.
好吧
All right.
我们去北方  清楚了吗
We're going north. Got it?
塔拉  怎么回事  怎么回事
Tara. What is it? What is it?
我不能...
I can't--
起来  起来
Get up, get up, get up.
这里左转
Turn left up here.
才短短五分钟
This is the third left turn
你就让我左转了三次
you've made me make in the last five minutes.
-你迷路了  -我没有
- You're lost. - I'm not.
左转
Turn left.
如果你迷路了  就说出来
If you're lost, please just tell me.
汽油可经不起你这样自负地折腾
The gas in this tank is worth more than your ego.
如果你想谈油耗  我们应该...
If you want to talk fuel efficiency, we could talk--
我们不能关上车窗
We are not rolling up the windows.
-里面一股腐臭味  -停车
- It smells like a damn carcass in here. - Stop the van.
为什么停车
Why are we stopping?
骗子[西语]
Mentirosa.
你是个骗子
Ugh, liar!
不是
Nope.
这不就是你的计划吗
This wasn't your plan?
不然你为什么坚持导航
Why you insisted on navigating?
还让他睡觉
Why you told him to go to sleep?
不  我不是说我没骗人
Nope. I never claimed otherwise.
这样吧  你为之前的诽谤道歉
Now how about you apologize for the slander
我们就算扯平了
and we call it square?
你他妈脑子有毛病吗
What the hell is wrong with you?
如果格伦和塔拉还活着  中途无停顿
If Glenn and Tara were still alive and there were no significant delays
且保持每小时约3英里的速度行进
and they continued traveling at approximately three miles per hour
我已在脑中精确推算过
and I timed it correctly in my head,
他们应该在这儿附近
they might be somewhere around here.
他们两个并非当务之急
Those two are not the priority.
当务之急是将你送到华府
The only priority is getting you to Washington.
等我拯救世界之后
After I save the world,
我不能带着愧疚活下去
I still have to live with myself.
我决不丢下他们
I'm not leaving them behind.
他娘的
Oh! Son of a bitch!
我们为什么停下
Why the hell are we stopped?
如果他们从隧道出来了
If they made it out of that tunnel,
应该会在这附近
they'd be somewhere around here.
你逗我玩呢  是吧
You're kidding me, right?
你怎么回事
What's your problem?
-我怎么回事  -开车的是你
- My problem? - You're the one in the driver's seat.
你踩的刹车
You're the one who put your damn foot on the brake.
是他让我停车的
He told me to stop.
那也不能停车  绝对不能
You don't stop! You never stop!
-我知道规矩  -如果你知道规矩
- I know the rules. - If you know the rules,
规矩就是绝不停车
the rule is never stop!
-如果停下来  -伙计们
- When you stop... - Guys!
-伙计们  -干嘛
- Guys! - What?
开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
老天
Christ.
交出来
Give it here.
后退
You step back.
我的半只兔子装在包里  现在没了
My half was in the bag. Now it's gone.
除了你  这里没人
Now ain't nobody around here
会对半只兔子感兴趣
interested in no half a damn cottontail except you.
不是吗
Ain't that right?
只有你还一直惦记着这点破事
You're the only one still thinking about that crap.
-把你的包倒空  -我说了后退
- Empty your bag. - I said step back.
你拿他的兔子了吗  达里尔
Did you take his rabbit, Daryl?
给我说实话
Just tell me the truth.
我什么也没拿
I didn't take nothing.
那我们看看
What do we got here?
出来呀
Come on.
看这个
Well, look at that.
是你放进去的吧
You put that there, didn't you?
趁我刚才出去撒尿
When I went out to take a piss.
-你骗人  -是不是
- You lied. - Didn't you?
你骗人
You lied.
就是你偷的
You stole.
我们要不要给这个白痴点教训  乔
We gonna teach this fool or what, Joe?
达里尔说他没拿你那半只兔子
Now, Daryl says he didn't take your half of the rabbit.
那我们遇到难题了
So we got a little conundrum here.
要么是他在撒谎
Either he's lying,
这是不可饶恕的罪行
which is an actionable offense,
或者
or...
不会是你故意栽赃陷害他吧
you didn't plant it on him like some pussy,
就像某个娘炮无能 骗人怂包的条子
punk-ass, cheating, coward cop, did you?
虽然严格来说  这不算违反规矩
'Cause while that wouldn't be specifically breaking the rules,
但是很令人失望
it'd be disappointing.
是啊
It would.
但不是我干的
I didn't.
好的
Good.
那么
Well...
教训他一下  弟兄们
Teach him a lesson, gents.
他就是个撒谎精  我受够了
He's a lying sack of shit. I'm sick of it.
好好教训他
Teach him all the way.
我看见是他干的
I saw him do it.
你为什么不阻止他
Why didn't you try to stop him?
他想耍花样  就让他耍
He wanted to play that out. I let him.
你说了真话
You told the truth.
他撒谎了
He lied.
你懂规矩
You understand the rules.
他不懂
He doesn't.
看来兔子头也归你了
Looks like you get the head, too.
你走吧  快走
Go. Go.
去找玛姬  找到玛姬
Find Maggie. Go find Maggie.
不行
No, no.
No.
格伦  你救不了我
Glenn, you can't save me.
即便你把石头挪开  我也跑不了
Even if you got this off me, I can't run.
如果你帮我  我们都会死在这里
And if you help me, they're gonna get both of us.
肯定有办法
There's got to be a way.
肯定有其它办法
There's got to be a different way.
格伦  它们过来了
Glenn, they're coming.
我不会走的  我不会丢下你
I'm not leaving. I'm not leaving you!
快离开
Get out of here!
走啊
Go!
不行
No.
来啊
Come on!
卧倒
Get down!
天啊  你太美了
God, you are so beautiful.
情况如何
How'd it go?
隧道那端布置好了
End of the tunnel's secure.
如果有东西要闯进来  我们会提前听到
If anything tries to come in, we'll hear in plenty of time.
我们还没正式认识
We didn't get to officially meet.
不好意思
Oh, I'm sorry.
塔拉  这是玛姬
Tara, this is Maggie.
玛姬  这是塔拉
Maggie, Tara.
他爱死你了
He's a big fan of yours.
我在路上碰到了塔拉
I met Tara on the road.
没有她我到不了这里
Couldn't have made it here without her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
她一听到我要做什么  就坚持要帮我
When she heard what I was doing, she said she had to help me.
她就是这样的人
She's just that kind of person.
怎么了
What's up?
他刚说
He just said
他知道灾变的原因
that he knows what caused the outbreak.
是的
Yeah.
他知道
He does.
让我猜猜  他让你跟他去华府是吗
Let me guess. He asked you to go to DC with him?
你们能找到彼此真让我感动
I'm downright tickled y'all found each other.
你们今晚应该好好庆祝一下
Should spend the rest of the night celebrating.
因为明天
Because tomorrow
我们八个人没有任何理由
there's absolutely no reason
不登上那辆货车
why the eight of us don't stuff ourselves
前往华府
in that van and head up to Washington.
他说得对
He's right.
我会去的
I'm gonna go.
不  他错了
No, he's wrong.
我们走了休斯顿到华府55%的路程
We're 55% of the way from Houston to Washington.
之前我们有装甲军车
Up until now, we've had an armored military vehicle
但还失去了八个人
for transport and we lost eight people.
-这不是我们的错  -他们死了
- That wasn't our fault. - They're gone.
开着那辆捡到的货车
I can't imagine we'd have better luck
我们的运气会更糟
with that grocery grabber we picked up.
离终点站步行只需一天
We're a day's walk from Terminus.
谁知道他们那里有什么
Who knows what they've got there?
听着  去看看也没坏处
Look, it couldn't hurt to check.
补充一些补给
Load up on supplies,
说不定还能
maybe even
招募他们的一些人跟我们走
recruit some of them to come with.
我跟你们去
I'll go with you guys,
之后再去
but after.
我要先去终点站看看
I have to see Terminus.
我哥哥可能在那里
My brother could be there.
我必须知道
I got to know.
我也是
Me, too.
两个原因都有
On both counts.
如果他说我是错的
He tells me I'm wrong...
我会听
I listen.
明天我们去终点站
Tomorrow we go to the end of the line.
然后去华府
Then Washington.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我知道  我们当时也在那里
I know. We were right over there.
冲来了一群行尸
A whole swarm of them came at us.
我们的弹药不够
And we didn't have enough bullets.
我试着想象你在这里会怎么做
I tried to think what you would do if you were here.
于是我对着房顶扫射
So I just emptied my clip into the ceiling
希望有奇迹发生
and I hoped for the best.
太夸张了
That's unreal.
就像你让他们别去拯救世界
Kind of like asking those guys to hold off
而是跟你去找妻子吗
saving the world while you go look for your wife?
我很有说服力
I'm a persuasive guy.
是啊
Yeah.
你在做什么
Whoa, hey. What are you doing?
抱歉
Sorry.
我只有你这一张照片
This is the only picture I have of you.
你不需要我的照片
You don't need a picture of me.
再也不需要了
You never will again.
私酿威士忌
White Lightning.
做法简单  用料很少
Easiest thing to make with the least amount of supplies.
我建议你慢点喝
I'd start slow if I was you.
你的胃可能比你想的更空
Your stomach's probably emptier than you think.
在一切崩溃之后
I ain't been lit at dawn since
我还没一大早喝醉过
before everything fell apart.
崩溃  我从来不这么想
Fell apart. I never looked at it like that.
我倒是觉得一切都有意义了
Seems to me like things are finally starting to fall together.
至少对我们这样的人而言
At least for guys like us.
像这样生活  求生存
Living like this, surviving.
我们以前就是这么做的  对吗
We've been doing this from the start, right?
更近了
Getting closer.
你之前见过吗
You seen this before?
是的
Oh, yeah.
我告诉你  这是个谎言
I'll tell you what it is. It's a lie.
根本没有能容纳所有人的避难所
Ain't no sanctuary for all.
反正不会欢迎你我这样的人
Ain't gonna welcome guys like you and me with open arms.
那我们是要去那里吗
So is that where we're headed?
现在想起来问了
So now you're asking?
是的
That's right.
我们当时在一栋房子里  没招谁惹谁
We were in a house minding our own business
结果有一个操蛋的人渣躲在房子里
and this walking piece of fecal matter was hiding in the home.
勒死了我们的同伴卢  让他变成了行尸
Strangled our colleague Lou and left him to turn.
卢袭击了我们所有人
Lou came at all of us.
他跑掉了
He lit out.
我们追踪他到了这些轨道上
We tracked him to these tracks,
看到这样的标志  然后决定去那里
one of those signs, and thus we've got a destination in mind.
你看到他的脸了吗
You see his face?
只有托尼看见了
Only Tony.
足够找他算账了
That's enough for a reckoning.
我要了
Claimed.
?Be not so nervous
?Be not so frail
?Someone watches you, you will not fail
终点站
?Be not so nervous, be not so frail
?Be not so sorry for what you've done
?You must forget them now, it's done
?When you wake up
?You'll find that you can run
?Be not so sorry for what you've done
终点站
?Be not so fearful
?Be not so pale
?Someone watches you
放下武器  你会得到款待
你已到达终点站
?You will not leave the rails
?Be not so fearful, be not so pale
?Be not so sorry for what you've done
?You must forget them now, it's done
?And when you wake up
?You'll find that you can run
?Be not so sorry for what you've done
我叫玛丽
I'm Mary.
看来你们在外面漂泊很久了
Looks like you've been on the road a while.
是的
We have.
我来把你们安顿好  给你们做点东西吃
Let's get you settled and we'll make you a plate.
欢迎来到终点站
Welcome to Terminus.